<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Finance Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.5</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 21:55:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Market Insghts - 21/07/24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-07_21_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 21:55:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-07_21_24/</guid>
      <description>Major Market Movements: Equities, Fixed Income, Commodities, and Currencies This past week witnessed significant turbulence across various asset classes, with equities, fixed income, commodities, and currencies all experiencing notable shifts. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the key events that influenced the markets.
Political Developments Donald Trump Assassination The assassination of former President Donald Trump sent shockwaves through the political landscape, creating immediate uncertainty and volatility in the markets. This unprecedented event has raised numerous questions about political stability and its impact on economic policies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Market Summary - 29/06/24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-06_29_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-06_29_24/</guid>
      <description>Federal Reserve Actions: The Federal Reserve decided to maintain its current policy stance in June. While the median staff projection anticipates a single rate cut in 2024 (down from three expected earlier), Fed Chair Powell hinted that up to two cuts could still occur by year-end, contingent on economic conditions rather than as firm projections. A potential rate adjustment in September hinges on further inflation moderation, otherwise, a cut may be postponed until late December.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bullet Movements - 09/06/24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-06_07_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-06_07_24/</guid>
      <description>European Central Bank cuts interest rates by a quarter basis point 4% to 3.7% (ECB deposite rate) Euro Stoxx 50 hitting a record high Nvidia overtakes Apple in achieving a 3 trillion dollar market value? Paris military company IPO&amp;rsquo;s, specialises in night vision goggles? Claudia - Mexico New President Brent Crude Oil down SAP acquistion of WalkMe 45% share premium Indian Feneral Elections - Bharatiya Janata Party, Other, Narendra Modi loses majority vote, Nifty 50 affected how, drop in indiace equities, MSCI India down Indian economy expected to grow 7% this year Diamond Index, synthetic lab grown diamonds are becoming more popular, Anglo American wants to seel of Debeers diamond production, does not fit with market model Traders place record level of bets that UK carbon credits will rise in the future US labour market data release, non-farm payroll employment increase by 272,000 in May and the unemployment rate changed little at 4.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bullet Movements - 31/05/24</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-05_31_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:39:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-05_31_24/</guid>
      <description>Weekly Stock Question
Price / Earnings Ratio (historically high or low) Sales, Net income, Operating margin, prodcuts, risks to their business Areas where they are growing Strengths (brand name, international exposure, and things that they have done recently) Pick a stock then steer back to the general economy Have to have an edge What is the edge on this trade? Why do you expect to make money? What is your stop loss on this trade and why?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverted Yield Curves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-05_26_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 22:59:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-05_26_24/</guid>
      <description>Market Update: Statistics Stay updated on the current market dynamics and key financial indicators that influence global economics and investment strategies.
Asset Current Value/Rate S&amp;amp;P 500 5,196.91 DJIA 3811.48 Crude Oil $77.91 Gold $2344.00 3M UST 5.39% 6M UST 5.36% 2 yr UST 4.95% 5 yr UST 4.58% 10 yr UST 4.5590% 30 yr UST 4.68% Recent News Currency Peak: The pound-to-euro exchange rate has reached its highest level in two years, indicating a significant shift in currency values.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interest &amp; Inflation Rates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-05_19_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 17:07:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-05_19_24/</guid>
      <description>Market News Raspberry Pi IPO: The British manufacturer of low-cost computer modules for industrial applications is planning to list on the London Stock Exchange. This move highlights the increasing market interest in affordable computing solutions.
US Inflation Update: US inflation has decreased to 3.4%, aligning with economists&amp;rsquo; predictions. This development has spurred investors to increase their bets on potential cuts to Federal Reserve interest rates. Notably, the inflation data from April last year will be phased out this week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Market Bullet Movements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-05_12_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 17:07:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-05_12_24/</guid>
      <description>Latest Market News and Highlights Chinese Bond Market Activity Chinese authorities have initiated the sale of ¥1 trillion ($140 billion) in long-dated bonds. This move aims to enhance liquidity in the market for longer-term Chinese bonds.
Foreign Exchange Hedging Amid Geopolitical Risks In the context of increasing geopolitical risks and diverging economies, hedging foreign exchange exposure has become increasingly crucial for global investors.
UK Economic Developments The UK GDP has grown by 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Market Bullet Movements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-05_05_24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 17:07:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/Finance-Blog/posts/post-05_05_24/</guid>
      <description>Amazon’s Cloud Dominance Continues: Amazon Web Services (AWS) showcased an impressive performance with a 17% year-on-year sales increase, totaling $25 billion in the first quarter of 2024. This marks a significant acceleration in AWS&amp;rsquo;s growth trajectory, reinforcing its leadership in the cloud computing sector.
Pharmaceutical Sector Highlights: Novo Nordisk&amp;rsquo;s Wegovy, a leading weight-loss drug, has propelled the company to become one of Europe’s most valued pharmaceutical firms. In a robust start to the year, drug developers have successfully raised $6.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
